<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>phenology on Jaime Ashander</title>
    <link>https://ashander.info/tags/phenology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in phenology on Jaime Ashander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2009 - 2019, Jaime Ashander</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ashander.info/tags/phenology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The mechanisms of phenology: the patterns and processes of phenological shifts</title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/posts/2018/10/phenology-mechanisms-pattern-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/posts/2018/10/phenology-mechanisms-pattern-process/</guid>
      <description>From the abstract
 Species across a wide range of taxa and habitats are shifting phenological events in response to climate change. While advances are common, shifts vary in magnitude and direction within and among species, and the basis for this variation is relatively unknown. We examine previously suggested patterns of variation in phenological shifts in order to understand the cue–response mechanisms that underlie phenological change. Here, we review what is known about the mechanistic basis for nine factors proposed to predict phenological change (latitude, elevation, habitat type, trophic level, migratory strategy, ecological specialization, species’ seasonality, thermoregulatory mode, and generation time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the joint effects of plastic and evolutionary change on demography from time series</title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/posts/2014/01/understanding-joint-effects-plastic-evolutionary-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/posts/2014/01/understanding-joint-effects-plastic-evolutionary-poster/</guid>
      <description>Background/Question/Methods
In nature, selection often fluctuates, but observed changes in traits may owe not only to selection but plasticity. Further, changes in traits due to selection and to plasticity do not have equal demographic effects: the cost of selection is paid through declines in population number or growth rate. Thus, observed trajectories of trait value and population number can depend on interactions between plasticity, evolution and environment. The extent to which these interactions affect observed trajectories depends on the demographic context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>