<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Etcs on Jaime Ashander</title>
    <link>https://ashander.info/etc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Etcs on Jaime Ashander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2009 - 2019, Jaime Ashander</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ashander.info/etc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-background/</guid>
      <description>Title: Background Template: etc
I am a Postdoctoral Scholar in the Shaffer lab at UCLA. Working in collaboration with Peter Ralph (now at U of Oregon), we are developing methods that use genomic data to inform demographic models of the desert tortoise (Gopherus agassizii). These models will enable us to analyze effects of scenarios for development in the Mojave desert on the population viability of the tortoise.
In September 2016, I received my Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-colaphon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-colaphon/</guid>
      <description> Title: This site Template: etc
A long-overdue website redesign. My overall goal is to combine personal academic website (papers, projects, CV, etc) along with a platform for quick blog-like entries (perhaps later adding disqus integration, share buttons etc).
Currently, pull data from figshare for results. Eventually I&amp;rsquo;d like to automatically pull data from other sources (eg github).
Details  templated (jinja2) index to pull from results (papers, preprints), themes (overall project categories) and notes (blog-like) will add projects (work in progress, github repos, project descriptions) as top-level category soon these categories are repeated on top nav rotating banner image with some shots from old website  Engine + hosting  Pelican engine for a static site to generate results, projects, notes from markdown hosting on github  Style  bootstrap, using bootswatch yeti via pelican-bootstrap3 very light additional css (eg padding elements) customizations to pelican-bootstrap3 include rotating banner bar (via javascript in base template), limiting sidebar display to blog-like (called notes here) entries, and adding neighbor arrows to blog posts  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-conflicts-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-conflicts-funding/</guid>
      <description>Title: Funding Template: etc
My postdoctoral research in the Shaffer lab at UCLA is funded by the US Fish and Wildlife Service.
My Ph.D. support has included a two-year traineeship with the REACH IGERT, as well as a one-year Bridge RA-ship funded through the same program.
My M.Sc. was supported largely by the Pacific Institute of Mathematical Sciences International Graduate Training Centre in mathematical biology. I also received a (1 year) University of Alberta Master&amp;rsquo;s Scholarship, which paid for tuition during my first term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/etc/etc-contact/</guid>
      <description>Title: Contact Template: etc
Current email (ucla dot edu):
ashander</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>