<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>floodplain on Jaime Ashander</title>
    <link>https://ashander.info/tags/floodplain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in floodplain on Jaime Ashander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2009 - 2019, Jaime Ashander</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ashander.info/tags/floodplain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EFI2019 talk: Ecological forecasts for integrated socio-environmental systems (SES)</title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/posts/2019/05/ecological-forecasting-integrated-ses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/posts/2019/05/ecological-forecasting-integrated-ses/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;&amp;ndash; Click the link for a video of the talk!
Forecasting or projecting involves a wide range of timescales and associated assumptions about human behavior. At one end of the spectrum are very-near-term physical forecasts (like the weather) and at another end are long-run, scenario-based projections (like global emissions pathways). Ecological forecasts span a range of timescales and assumptions about human behavior. The main message of this talk was that in developing and thinking about &amp;ldquo;ecological forecasting&amp;rdquo; as a discipline, we must be clear about whether and to what extent a forecast is incorporating human behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal investment to enable evolutionary rescue</title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/posts/2019/03/optimal-investement-evolutionary-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/posts/2019/03/optimal-investement-evolutionary-rescue/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response of fish biota to dams in the Lower Colorado River Basin: empirical findings and utility for predicting responses to climate and water use change</title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/posts/2014/05/response-fish-biota-lower-colorado-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/posts/2014/05/response-fish-biota-lower-colorado-river/</guid>
      <description>The biologists have done their jobs. We know the life cycles and habitat requirements of endangered western fishes&amp;hellip; [A] successful management program could be devised and implemented for the Grand Canyon region. Current politics stand in the way, just as surely as politics of the 1960s aided and abetted our efforts to learn enough to save this fauna. &amp;ndash; W. L. Minckley (1991)
Over the past century, development of the Colorado River Basin for water resources changed a dynamic river into a managed system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying River-Floodplain Systems: A Historical and Ecological Perspective</title>
      <link>https://ashander.info/posts/2012/10/igert-workshop-pres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://ashander.info/posts/2012/10/igert-workshop-pres/</guid>
      <description>This presentation made 9&amp;frasl;14 at the UC Davis REACH IGERT Floodplains workshop, by Jaime Ashander, Kelly Gravuer, Megan Kelso, Mary E. Mendoza, Noam Ross</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>