<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jaime Ashander</title><link href="http://ashander.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ashander.github.io/feeds/themes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ashander.github.io/</id><updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Rapid evolution, local adaption, and model-data connections</title><link href="http://ashander.github.io/posts/2011/06/phd-initial-summary/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Jaime Ashander</name></author><id>tag:ashander.github.io,2011-06-29:posts/2011/06/phd-initial-summary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Ph.D. is focused on modelling populations that exhibit rapid responses to enviornmental change.
Potential applications include salmon, annual plants, and infectious disease.
I'm particularly interested in transient dynamics, connecting models to data, and forecasting.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Ph.D."></category><category term="local adaptation"></category><category term="evolution"></category><category term="stochasticity"></category><category term="transient dynamics"></category><category term="population biology"></category></entry><entry><title>Population biology in regulated rivers: application to regulation and restoration</title><link href="http://ashander.github.io/posts/2010/09/population-biology-in-regulated-rivers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Jaime Ashander</name></author><id>tag:ashander.github.io,2010-09-29:posts/2010/09/population-biology-in-regulated-rivers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGERT project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CO River Class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="floodplains"></category><category term="salmon"></category><category term="restoration"></category><category term="applied ecology"></category><category term="population biology"></category><category term="Grand Canyon"></category><category term="optimization"></category><category term="economics"></category></entry><entry><title>Effects of parasite exchange among farm and wild salmon</title><link href="http://ashander.github.io/posts/2010/08/parasite-exchange/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Jaime Ashander</name></author><id>tag:ashander.github.io,2010-08-29:posts/2010/08/parasite-exchange/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My master's research focused on the evolutionary ecology of sea lice,
   farmed and wild salmon. I'm particularly interested in the ways in
   which the combination of wild salmon migrations and salmon farm
   management can influence chemical resistance evoultion on farms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sea lice tend to proliferate on sea-cage farmed salmon, resulting in
economic costs to the farmers. These outbreaks can also affect wild
populations, which raises concerns about population conservation and
the environmental costs of sea-cage aquaculture. Salmon farmers
address these concerns with integrated pest management (IPM)
strategies that include chemical treatments. These chemicals can
reduce parasite numbers, but over time, parasites can develop a
resistance to the chemicals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In coastal B.C. new conservation regimes rely on increased use of
  chemical treatments, which is classically associated with resistance
  emergence. Achieving conservation goals could then actually
  &lt;em&gt;increase&lt;/em&gt; the risk of resistance emergence; however, flow of
  susceptible genes from lice on wild fish into populations on farms
  could delay resistance emergence (similar to "refuge" planting in
  agriculture).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wild salmon demography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustained exchange of parasites between wild and farmed salmon,
  combined with wild salmon migrations can alter dynamical patterns in
  salmon populations. Notably, patterns of line dominance in pink
  salmon may change in the presence of farms.  Line dominance can
  either increase or decrease, depending on the way in which salmon
  farms respond to infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a follow-up study, coworkers and I show that sustained spill-back
into wild reservoir hosts can result in an Allee effect in the wild
hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Parasite evolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goal&lt;/em&gt;: Understand feedbacks between increasing chemical use,
 conservation and resistance management in the context of sea lice,
 wild salmon and salmon farms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/em&gt;: Wild salmon serve as evolutionary refuges, slowing
resistance evolution in sea lice. &lt;!--, and thus provide an
_ecosystem service_. --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;How do wild salmon migrations near farms affect time to resistance emergence?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifically, how do
  management actions (treatment, stocking density) affect time to
  resistance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the effects of biological assumptions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;How does varying synchrony of treatments on groups of farms change things?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="sea lice"></category><category term="salmon"></category><category term="resistance evolution"></category><category term="complex population dynamics"></category><category term="population biology"></category><category term="mathematical ecology"></category></entry></feed>