<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Jaime Ashander</title>
    <link>https://www.ashander.info/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Jaime Ashander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2009 - 2019, Jaime Ashander</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ashander.info/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So, you did some GLMs &amp; compared with AIC. Congrats!</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/10/model-selection-glms-aic-what-to-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/10/model-selection-glms-aic-what-to-report/</guid>
      <description>Here’s what you need to report in a paper about the model comparison:
residual devianceresidual dfdelta AICAIC weightYou should also report the null deviance and degrees of freedom,maybe in a table caption.
Thanks to Emilio Bruna for prompting this post andsuggesting its title. (Update 2015-12-14: thanks also to Ben Bolker for pointing out some issues in the first version of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy alternatives to bar charts in native R graphics</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/04/barchart-alternatives-in-base-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/04/barchart-alternatives-in-base-r/</guid>
      <description>It’s a long tradition in statistical graphics going from Tufte back toTukey andClevelandto advise against using bar charts. Many folks, includingme, have pejorativelycalled the common (in ecology, at least) bar chart + SE a “dynamite plot”.Although Ben Bolker has questionedthe wisdom of this sentiment, I think in most cases they’re worth avoiding. (I discuss this morein “When and here are dynamite plots appropriate” below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing fits, inference, implications of (G)LMMs</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/04/d-rug-mixed-effects-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/04/d-rug-mixed-effects-viz/</guid>
      <description>In a live walk-through on April 10 at the Davis R-Users Group, I gave a brief presentationmotivating this topic.This post expands and cleans up the code from that talk. If you justwant the code: download the .R file.
Updated 2015-04-28
The point of this post isn’t the statistics of mixed models. For that, learningthe experimental design and statistics behind modern mixed models, I recommendsome relatively recent papers below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Between-generation bet-hedging</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/01/between-generation-bet-hedging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2015/01/between-generation-bet-hedging/</guid>
      <description>Version of notes for discussion I led in Sebastain Schreiber&amp;rsquo;s for PBG 271 Research Conference in Ecology on &amp;ldquo;Life history evolution in stochastic environments&amp;rdquo;.
Reading Childs et al and Stearn&amp;rsquo;s piece on Bernoulli Childs, Metcalf and Rees (2010) present a plant-focused review of bet-hedging, including a review of essential theory. As in many papers on bet-hedging, these authors distiguish between conservative and diversified strategies.
Geometic mean fitness concept  When fitness is temporally variable, the appropriate measure of evolutionary success is the expected geometric mean growth rate of a genotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Central Valley long ago</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2011/07/unhealth-plain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2011/07/unhealth-plain/</guid>
      <description> The plain is unhealthy and infested with mosquitos in incredible numbers and of unparalleled ferocity &amp;mdash; William Brewer, 1861
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobless recovery and growth-signalling autonomy</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2010/01/jobless-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2010/01/jobless-recovery/</guid>
      <description>We help companies to grow by helping them to raise capital&amp;hellip; Companies that grow create wealth. This, in turn, allows people to have jobs that create more growth and more wealth. It&amp;rsquo;s a virtuous cycle. We have a social purpose. &amp;mdash; Lloyd Blankfein
 Ed Abbey wrote that Blankfein&amp;rsquo;s virtuous cycle, growth for the sake of growth, is &amp;ldquo;the logic of the cancer cell&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you buy this anti-captialist mumbo jumbo, there is something cancerous about a jobless, finance-led recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science education and uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/12/science-is-uncertain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/12/science-is-uncertain/</guid>
      <description>A brand new &amp;ldquo;-gate&amp;rdquo; on the climate science front has me thinking about the relationship between science and the public. A big issue in communicating science stems from the fundamental disconnect between science as practiced and science as taught in introductory formats, e.g. in high school.
Most people learn science as fact. The reality is emerging scientific knowledge (in fact all scientific knowledge) is uncertain. Those who disagree idealogically with the state of scientific knowlege highlight this uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrong, not confused</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/11/wrong-not-confused/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/11/wrong-not-confused/</guid>
      <description>Quoting Turchin (1998) quoting Hull (1988) quoting Bacon (?) :
 In science it is better to be wrong than confused.
 The point is, though a mathematical model that purports to repesent reality will be wrong, one with clear definitions and assumptions can be helpful. Mathematical modeling is a tool to move from confusion about a process to making clear (if wrong) statements about that process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negative results or technical problems?</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/11/omitting-negative-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/11/omitting-negative-results/</guid>
      <description>True or false: &amp;ldquo;Non-publication of negative results is extraordinarily common in science&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; ?
This comes from biomed world, specifically protein design, where some awesome claims&amp;mdash;design of protein receptors to detect TNT (the explosive) among other things&amp;mdash;have come under scrutiny. The lab involved recently retracted some other work.
The quotation above is from Loren Looger, who was a PhD student on the project. He&amp;rsquo;s referrring to unreported instances where a designed protein didn&amp;rsquo;t bind the target and concludes that the omission &amp;ldquo;did not seem inappropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salish Sea</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/salish-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/salish-sea/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Salish Sea&amp;rdquo; is on its way to being an official name in the U.S. and Canada. Can Cascadia be far behind?
Stefan Freelan at WWU made the beautiful map of the region here. His page has lots of details about the region and the history of the term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisker as integral</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/whisker-integral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/whisker-integral/</guid>
      <description>An NYT column reports on fur seal whiskers serving as biogeochemical records. This kind of data is more and more common, e.g. otoliths, feathers, shells. What can scientists do with it?
I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly seen biogeochemical markers used to infer relatively static traits of individual like origin and age or to make coarse-scale statements about diet (trophic level). The fur seal study got trophic information at a bit finer scale (within-year variation), connecting that to yearly migrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Par avion</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/voting-from-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/voting-from-canada/</guid>
      <description>Today I mailed my absentee ballot for the S.F. municipal election. The Good People footed the bill to send it up here to me in Edmonton, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether they intended to spring for the return journey.
The only clue was the cryptic (to me) &amp;ldquo;U.S. Postage Paid. 39 USC 3406. PAR AVION&amp;rdquo; printed in the upper right hand corner of the return envelope. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it would say &amp;lsquo;par avion&amp;rsquo; if they weren&amp;rsquo;t intending to pay, but if they were why would it say &amp;lsquo;U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market substitution in aquaculture</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/market-substitution-aquaculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/10/market-substitution-aquaculture/</guid>
      <description>A recent article in BioScience [1] focused on the relationship between aquaculture and conservation. This topic is quite interesting to me, but it&amp;rsquo;s obviously subtle. I don&amp;rsquo;t have well-defined thoughts except that (i) aquaculture could theoretically relieve pressure on some wild fisheries and (ii) certain aquaculture operations have proven negative impacts on some ecosystems.
This paper aims to highlight broad trends in capture and culture fisheries and quantify effects on biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian lag</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/09/canadian-lag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2009/09/canadian-lag/</guid>
      <description>The Coastal Voices blog at Living Oceans had an intersting post up remarking on the disparity between Canadian&amp;rsquo;s self-image as environmental progressives and reality&amp;mdash;that they appeaer to lag the U.S. in marine protection and other conservation issues. The author wondered why this might be. I left a comment, which I&amp;rsquo;ll expand on here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had similar thoughts and my guess is this blind spot for domestic environmental issues owes to Canada&amp;rsquo;s: (i) vast wild-lands (natural resources), (ii) very low population and (iii) long-standing economic dependence on extraction of those resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>