<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SESYNC on Jaime Ashander</title>
    <link>https://www.ashander.info/tags/sesync/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SESYNC on Jaime Ashander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2009 - 2019, Jaime Ashander</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ashander.info/tags/sesync/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive tools for integrated socio-environmental systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/themes/predictive-ecology-ses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/themes/predictive-ecology-ses/</guid>
      <description>Combining dynamical population ecology models with policy scenarios is an
important approach in both population biology and bioeconomics.
At its best, this approach may provide predictive understanding of future behavior.
But in complex socio-environmental systems (SES),
applying such theory requires large amounts of data and system understanding.
Reduced-complexity representations, like networks, provide promise but are not
yet linked to dynamic theory.
I am Co-leading a SESYNC working group focused on addressing this gap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EFI2019 talk: Ecological forecasts for integrated socio-environmental systems (SES)</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2019/05/ecological-forecasting-integrated-ses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/posts/2019/05/ecological-forecasting-integrated-ses/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;&amp;ndash; Click the link for a video of the talk!
Forecasting or projecting involves a wide range of timescales and associated assumptions about human behavior. At one end of the spectrum are very-near-term physical forecasts (like the weather) and at another end are long-run, scenario-based projections (like global emissions pathways). Ecological forecasts span a range of timescales and assumptions about human behavior. The main message of this talk was that in developing and thinking about &amp;ldquo;ecological forecasting&amp;rdquo; as a discipline, we must be clear about whether and to what extent a forecast is incorporating human behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Management of freshwater-coupled human-natural systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/themes/population-biology-in-human-dominated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>ashander AT rff org (Jaime Ashander)</author>
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/themes/population-biology-in-human-dominated/</guid>
      <description>Human livelihoods and ecosystem fates are often linked by water.
I have a longstanding interest in the population biology of rivers,
and in using theory and methods from computational ecology to understand
and manage rivers to sustain aquatic life and nature&amp;rsquo;s benefits to people.
I am co-leading a SESYNC working group focused on
systems where shallow aquifers link groundwater use to instream flows,
leading to tradeoffs between users and potential tipping points.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>